TRENT HAND

PROFILE

Highly dependable Software Developer and enthusiastic team player dedicated to streamlining processes and efficiently resolving project issues. A highly desirable combination of client-facing experience with solid programming skills creates a wealth of opportunities for excellence.

PROJECTS

Django Comic Book Store

Custom website built entirely within the Django framework using Stripe to facilitate credit card purchases. Styling is customized using CSS and Javascript to enhance front-end functionality not readily available in Python.

https://github.com/TrentHand/ComicStore

TrentSnaps

An iOS Snapchat clone storing data through Firebase. This is using CocoaPods to import features into my apps, primarily Firebase. This application mirrors the popular social networking app SnapChat. Users can take a photo, add a description, and send the photo to a friend. After the recipient views the photo and exits, the photo is deleted and no longer accessible. The sign-in is simplified: users enter an email/password. If the user already exists, they are signed in. If not, TrentSnaps will create a user for them.

https://github.com/TrentHand/ComicStore

BookCollector

An iOS app built entirely from Swift. Users are able to snap a photo with their phone, add a title, and store the book locally on the device. This app was created so I could remember books I've already purchased when shopping at our local bookstore.

https://github.com/TrentHand/Swift_Book_Collector

GottaGetGit

Teaching is a passion of mine. This is a presentation I gave to a local FreeCodeCamp study group to help them understand Git/Github more fully. Slides are included in the comments to the video.

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZHL80-Ts_Vk

SKILLS

Swift Xcode

Javascript AngularJS

SQL Python

Django Salesforce

Git/Github jQuery

EXPERIENCE

SALESFORCE ADMINISTRATOR, JOSHUA HARR SHANE FOUNDATION EAST WINDSOR, NJ – 2017-PRESENT

- * Update contacts from various donor organizations to ensure current information
- * Integrate 3rd party apps for use with other software platforms, like Eventbrite
- * Design workflow processes to increase efficiency among volunteers
- * Schedule campaigns for events held by JHSF
- * Train other members on proper use of Salesforce
- Basic VisualForce and Apex development
- * This is a volunteer position

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

NASHVILLE, TN - 2016-2017

- Daily hands on application of OOP fundamentals through group and individual projects.
- * Created single page applications in JavaScript in the AngularJS framework as well as HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and Materialize.
- Worked with jQuery for JavaScript libraries
- Project management/tracking with Trello and GitHub Issue Tracking
- Solution Design: white-boarding and wireframes
- Leveraged Django for creating and editing MVC applications

Experience cont.

- * Deployed applications through Firebase, GitHub and Digital Ocean
- * Source code/version control with Git/GitHub
- * Created servers and RESTful API's with Django REST framework
- * Retrieved and stored database information in Firebase and SQLite and PostgreSQL
- Practiced TDD with Python's unit test framework

- * Primary responsibilities involved selling home and auto insurance products to new home owners.
- * Cultivated relationships with local lenders and real estate agents to produce warm leads for my agency.
- * Train new employees on the software and systems used to produce insurance.

ACCOUNT EXECUTIVE, BLR BRENTWOOD, TN - 2014-2015

- * Positioned web portal solutions designed to ensure compliance and reduce administrative task time for professionals in the Human Resources Industry.
- * Salesforce experience as a user.
- * 500% YTD Attainment

SMALL BUSINESS ACCOUNT EXECUTIVE, COMCAST NASHVILLE, TN - 2014-2014

- * Outside sales position responsible for canvasing, qualifying, presenting, and finalizing the sale of Comcast SMB services.
- * Salesforce experience as a user.
- 223% quota attainment

ENGLISH AS A SECOND LANGUAGE TEACHER, SULEMON SECONDARY SCHOOL ANTALYA, TURKEY – 2012-2014

- * Taught children ages 5-16
- * Adult classes given for business professionals in the evenings
- Primarily taught through interactive engagements (songs, pop culture references, local field trips)
- Certified TESOL teacher

STORAGE AND SERVER SPECIALIST, DELL

NASHVILLE, TN - 2010-2012

- Positioned technical solutions for large data center deployments, involving at least \$50K/ year in annual IT spend.
- * Divided time between uncovering new projects, creating technical solutions, positioning the Dell solution in relation to the competition, completing the sales process with an order from the client, and following up to ensure the solution was performing as expected.
- * Heavy Salesforce experience as a user at this position, including providing feedback for processes, reporting metrics, and overall usability of the implemented system.
- * Consistently achieved and exceeded sales quotas with a high level of client satisfaction
- * Top Ten Rep, 4 quarters, outperforming set quota and all metrics.
- * #1 Sales Rep in division, 2 quarters
- * 1st round pick for all advanced Sales and Technical Trainings
- * 3 promotions in two years

INSIDE SALES REPRESENTATIVE, SPRINT NASHVILLE, TN – 2009-2010

- * Assisted walk-in clients with selection of mobile technology, evaluated home and business needs, upsold accessories and digital add-ons.
- * Followed up with clients post-purchase to ensure repeat business and long-term customer satisfaction.
- * Highest sales in store 9 out of 13 months.
- * Highest in accessory and peripheral sales 11 out of 13 months.
- * Four time Employee of the Month

LEAD OUTSIDE SALES TRAINER, MAXIMUS MARKETING

NASHVILLE, TN - 2006-2009

- * Produced technically apt and motivated sales representatives in a completely performance-based pay system.
- * Maintained personal production goals while training new representatives.
- * Conducted in-office meetings, training, interviews, evaluations, and terminations.
- * Major clients included At&t and IMS(a division of Quicken).
- Trained and sold on Retail, Consumer door-to-door, and Business-to-Business campaigns
- Held in-field interviews of potential new hires to determine sales aptitude

Experience continued

- * Managed a team of nine salespeople.
- * Worked on seven different campaigns in three years, a company record
- Test piloted and developed sales process for three campaigns
- * Two time National Rep of the Month
- Top Leader Award
- * Top Gun Sales Award

INSURANCE PRODUCER, AMERICAN INCOME LIFE NASHVILLE, TN – 2005-2006

- Primarily serviced union workers and their families
- * Products included a funeral benefit and paycheck replacement
- * Commission-based outside sales role

CARPENTRY/MASONRY SPECIALIST, US ARMY CORP OF ENGINEERS BAGRAM, AFGHANISTAN – 2003-2005

- * Served with the 926th Engineering Battalion out of Birmingham, AL
- * Primary objectives were to expand our troop footprint and improve living conditions
- * As a unit, we built a prison foundation, tripled the size of a large air base, and quadrupled the size of a Forward Operating Base
- * Selected to be the Lieutenant's assistant, requiring me to track the placement of our platoon's troops, the current status of our missions, and any other needs of the officers
- * Awarded the Army Commendation Medal and the Army Medal of Achievement

EDUCATION

PUBLIC RELATIONS, MIDDLE TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY

MURFREESBORO, TN - 2005